

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211













Total Experience: 19 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Automobile]

Notice Period: 1 Month

Enterprise Architect for developing reusable web components supporting Fintech integrations using emerging and latest web technologies. Experienced in delivering next generation financial portals catering to wealth and investment managers.

Current Designation: Group Manager, Application

Development and Delivery

Current Company: BNYMellon Technology India

Current Location: Chennai

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore. Chennai. Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Head/VP/GM-Technology(IT)/CTO Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Strategic Planning, Risk Analysis, Javascript, Html5, CSS, Spring Boot, Java/J2EE, Enterprise Web Architect, Angular, Mcroservices, REST, Application Development and Delivery, Financial Domain, Private Cloud, Fintech

Integration. Web Components. Web Security Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021

Last Modified: Jan-Mar 2021

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills | Work Authorization

Summary

19 years of web experience delivering next generation financial portals catering to wealth and investment managers.

Architect and implement strategic reusable web solutions for enterprise applications

Responsible for research, proposal and adoption of emerging web technologies

Manage development and delivery of multiple web teams

Collaborate with our strategic clients on delivering the best experience to users

Improve client experience by providing state of the art web solutions

Develop and manage more than 130 online investment and wealth management portals spanning more than 500 clients with focus on risk, resiliency and security

Work Experience

BNYMellon Technology India as Group Manager, Application Development and Delivery Jul 2001 to Till Date

Integrated Wealth Experience - Next Gen Portal 2018 - 2019

Redesigned our professional brokerage platform to provide a unified and integrated experience to wealth management

Architected next generation portal framework using Angular7, RxJs, Node

RESTful services deployed as Spring Boot micro services using Docker containers in private cloud

Architected model for exposing business features as Angular feature modules with ability to perform federated builds and deployments

Achieved improved time to market, high performing and resilient web application

Integration Strategy for Enterprise 2019 - Present

With integration becoming a critical part of financial services, we are developing technology that will help speed up our integration with our clients

Tighter integration of features with clients to provide improved user experience

Designed and implemented integration strategy using Angular 7 / Elements with ability to operate in any client environment

Collaborate with our strategic clients on delivering the best experience to users

Service Discovery/Gateway Service 2018 - 2019

Enterprise gateway service to route REST endpoints to microservices.

Provided architecture to find and route to services deployed in private cloud. Helped overcome shortcomings with Traefik

Service registered and discovered via Consul. Service routing and load balancing done using spring Ribbon Client Strategic Initiatives 2001 - Present

Architected and provided governance for the below strategic initiatives -

Site Builder - Turnkey solution for clients to build / customize websites. Greatly improved turn around time to rollout new websites

Architected white label solution for portals using StoreFront, Crafter CMS, SASS

Content Delivery Network - In-house CDN to host and deploy static artifacts with caching ability. 30% improvement in nage load time

Important

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

pago ioaa uiiio.

Retail Investor Platform Redesign - Single Page Application. Converted monolithic application to micro services model.

Reduced operational cost by 34%

Intelligently prefetch user data based on predictive analysis and Storm. Achieved faster page load time and efficient usage of resources.

First RIA application developed in 2009 using Dojo / JSF - MyFaces

Developed thin webclients using C.

Visual automation testing framework using AppliTools.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Automobile) from MADRAS INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY in 2001

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Represented our technical team at INSITE conference in Florida and Orlando

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

	Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
	Angular, Javascript, Dojo, HTML5			
	CSS, RxJs, Node			
	Java, J2EE, REST, Spring Boot			

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Tamil				

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General US Work Status: Need H1 Visa

Physically Challenged: No

Countries: India
Job Type: Permanent
Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.